With NAT, three kinds of address translations
can occur as a request from a private address
is attached to a public IP address. First, we
have NAT that takes place where every private
IP address that makes a request gets a public
IP address to use. This process is a rare way
to do NAT as most homes and businesses
have only one public IP address to use.
Another way to do NAT is to use a NAT pool
where a private IP address request uses an
available public IP address from a pool of IP
addresses. This process can be problematic.
Say there are five public IP addresses in a pool
and 20 devices with private IP addresses making
requests, then 15 devices will need to wait
for a public IP address to become available.
The most common form of NAT is Port NAT, often
known as Port Address Translation. In this setup,
each private IP address request gets assigned a
port from a public IP address. This combination
of public IP address and port is used to send
a request for data to another network. Then,
when the data is received, the router knows
what port number matches up with the private IP
address requesting the data, and then the data
is sent to the device that requested the data.